Register of the Survey of Race Relations records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Major Documents, 1905-1926 (Boxes 24-32)
  - Testimonial meeting on the Oriental, I.W.W. Hall, Cordova Street, 1924 March 4 (Box-folder 24: 16)
  - Call, T. M. Whaun, 1924 March 5 (Box-folder 24: 17)
  - Dinner, Dr. Lew, Seto More, Dr. Park, Miss Raushenbush, 1924 March 6 (Box-folder 24: 18)
  - Interview, Louie Houie, 1924 March (Box-folder 24: 19)
  - Visit, the Lam family, 1924 March (Box-folder 24: 20)
  - Visit, Miss Hellaby, Anglican missionary, 1924 March 10 (Box-folder 24: 21)
  - The Main Street of Chinatown via Mrs. Quong, 1924 March 12 (Box-folder 24: 22)
    8 pages; British Columbia
  - Luncheon, Miss Hosang, 1924 March 19 (Box-folder 24: 23)
    9 pages; British Columbia
  - Interview, Herbert Wang, 1924 March 25 (Box-folder 24: 24)
  - Visit, the old men's home, 1924 April 1 (Box-folder 24: 25)
  - Dinner, Louie Houie, President of the Merchants' Association, 1924 April 2 (Box-folder 24: 26)
    11 pages; British Columbia
  - Interview with J. A. Russel, barrister, criminal lawyer for the Chinese, 1924 April 30 (Box-folder 24: 27)
  - Audience, Thomas Moore Whaun, 1924 May 7 (Box-folder 24: 28)
  - Interview with Gershon Lew, the hottest bolshevik in Vancouver, 1924 May (Box-folder 24: 29)
  - A Chinese minister in revolt (Box-folder 24: 30)
  - Tea with Harry Hastings, the half-breed Chinese intellectual of Victoria, 1924 May 26 and 30 (Box-folder 24: 31)
  - Interview with Harry Hastings regarding the school strike and other matters, 1924 May 26 and 30 (Box-folder 24: 32)
  - Interview with Joe Hope, President of the Chinese Canadian Club, Victoria, 1924 May 26 (Box-folder 24: 33)
  - Interview with Cecil Lee, a native son who is married to a Hakkla, 1924 May 26-June 1 (Box-folder 24: 34)
  - Description of Cumberland, supposed to be the only place in the United States or Canada where Chinese and Japanese are mining underground, 1924 June 3 and 4 (Box-folder 24: 35)
    12 pages; British Columbia
  - Interview with Sanji Miyamoto, Hawaiian-born Japanese boy's American adventure, 1924 April 17 (Box-folder 24: 36)
    5 pages; Washington
  - Interview with Koreaki Kimura, a son of a successful Japanese business man, Seattle, 1924 April 22 (Box-folder 24: 37)
    3 pages; Washington
  - Interview with Hideo Robert Tashima, a son of the first Japanese mother in America, Seattle, 1924 April 17 (Box-folder 24: 38)
    6 pages; Washington
  - Interview with Takanaga Hirai, a Hawaiian Japanese immigrant, Seattle, 1924 March 21 (Box-folder 24: 39)
    7 pages; Washington
  - Interview with Masao Nishio, a Japanese school boy, 1924 April 22 (Box-folder 24: 40)
    4 pages; Washington
  - Interview with Tatsuji Suga, a visiting student, Seattle, 1924 April 22 (Box-folder 24: 41)
    2 pages; Washington
  - Murder case – British Columbia (Box-folder 24: 42)
    17 pages; British Columbia
  - Interview with Mrs. K. Nakashima, a picture bride, 1924 April 15 (Box-folder 24: 43)
  - Interview with Chiye Shigemura, a representative of the second generation, 1924 April 18 (Box-folder 24: 44)
  - Interview with Mrs. Toyo Shinowara, a teacher in a Japanese language school, 1924 June 4 (Box-folder 24: 45)
    4 pages, Washington
  - Interview with Mrs. Suie Murakami, a Japanese physician's wife, Mrs. Tashiro, interpreter, 1924 June 4 (Box-folder 24: 46)
  - Life history of a Puerto Rican (Box-folder 24: 47)
    14 pages; Southern California
  - Paper by a Japanese student in reply to a questionnaire on race relations (Box-folder 24: 48)
    4 pages; Northern California
  - Resolutions unanimously adopted by the Fifth Annual Convention of the American Legion, San Francisco, California, 1923 October 15-19 (Box-folder 24: 49)
    26 pages; Northern California
  - The Orientals in the Alaska salmon industry: First hand observations of Max Stern, Daily News (Box-folder 24: 50)
    13 pages; Northern California
  - Digital copy of Box 25
  - "The Land of Opportunity: Exterior View (or, from Migrant to Minister," by Jose P. Ruiz (Box-folder 25: 51)
    9 pages; Northern California
  - Tongs (Box-folder 25: 52)
    3 pages; Northern California
  - "My Oriental Husbands," by Emma Fong Kuno (Box-folder 25: 53)
    31 pages; Northern California
  - "Story of a Chinese College Girl," by Mrs. R. E. Park? (Box-folder 25: 54)
    12 pages; Northern California
  - "Miss Higgins of the Presbyterian Mission Speaks," by Mrs. R. E. Park? (Box-folder 25: 55)
    6 pages; Northern California
  - Story of a Chinese girl student (Box-folder 25: 56)
    10 pages; Northern California
  - Diary of a schoolteacher, Imperial Valley, 1924 April 6 (Box-folder 25: 57)
    28 pages; Southern California
  - Life history of Sakoe Tsuboi, University of Southern California (Box-folder 25: 58)
    6 pages; Southern California
  - Chapter IV: "California as a Nation-State and Civilization Frontier from International Contact at the Frontier," by Kiyo Sue Inui (Box-folder 25: 59)
  - "The Life History as a Social Document," by Hideo Oyama, University of Southern California, 1924 June 5 (Box-folder 25: 60)
    7 pages; Southern California
  - Letter to Dr. Daugherty concerning Quon Gay, and document written by Quon Gay, 1924 June 9 (Box-folder 25: 61)
    3 pages; Southern California
  - "Case Brief on Anglo-Japanese Marriage: A Brief Relation of the Inter-Racial Married Life of Elizabeth Coote and Toyotomi Ujimasa," by L. G. Schroeder, 1924 June 18 (Box-folder 25: 62)
    11 pages; Southern California
  - The United States of America (Plaintiff) versus Sakharam Ganesh Pandit (Defendant) (Box-folder 25: 63)
    8 pages; Southern California
  - "Anti-Japanese Agitation in Hollywood," by William C. Smith, University of Southern California (Box-folder 25: 64)
    37 pages; Southern California
  - "A Study of the Japanese Language Schools in California," by Ken Ishikawa, translation (Box-folder 25: 65)
  - "The Life History as a Social Document," by Isaak G. Granadosin, University of Southern California (Box-folder 25: 66)
    10 pages; Southern California
  - "Assyrian Situation in Turlock, California," by William C. Smith, University of Southern California, 1924 July 1 (Box-folder 25: 67)
    5 pages; Southern California
  - "Preliminary Statement of Racial Relations Between Chinese Students in an American University," by H. J. McMath, special student in sociology, University of Southern California (Box-folder 25: 68)
  - "The Life History as a Social Document," by Chotoku Toyama, 1924 May 27 (Box-folder 25: 69)
    18 pages; Southern California
  - "Japanese in the City of Los Angeles," abridged from a master's thesis by Gretchen Tuthill, 1924 June (Box-folder 25: 70)
    42 pages; Southern California
  - "Interview with Reverend John M. Yamazaki," Pastor of the Japanese Episcopal Mission, Los Angeles, by Chloe Holt, 1924 July 13 (Box-folder 25: 71)
    7 pages; Race consciousness, Americanization, Goodwill: Religious activities; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interview with W. S. Fawcett, El Centro, California (Box-folder 25: 71)
    3 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture and labor; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mrs. C. S. Machida," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 25: 73)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Intermarriage; Chinese and Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Second Generation," interview with Reverend K. S. Itow, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 12 (Box-folder 25: 74)
    2 pages; Americanization, Goodwill: Religious activities, Social disorganization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Second Generation," interview with K. Yokosawa, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 19 (Box-folder 25: 75)
    2 pages; Americanization: Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Lillie Leung,' by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 12 (Box-folder 25: 76)
    3 pages; Americanization: Vocational problems, Race consciousness; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Susie Yamamoto," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 9 (Box-folder 25: 77)
    3 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness, Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Seiichi Nobe," by William C. Smith, 1924 August 11 (Box-folder 25: 78)
    6 pages; Americanization, Goodwill: Religious activities, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with G-- S--," American-born Japanese, by William C. Smith, 1924 August 19 (Box-folder 25: 79)
    3 pages; Americanization: Family problems, Goodwill: Religious activities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Chiyo," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 14 (Box-folder 25: 80)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Vocational problems and family problems, Goodwill: Religious activities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mary Nobe," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 25: 81)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Race consciousness, Social disorganization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Japanese Valedictorian of Franklin High School," Seattle, Washington, by Ruth H. Greiner (Box-folder 25: 82)
    8 pages; Race consciousness, Americanization: Education; Japanese; Seattle
  - Life history – Rose, slave girl (Box-folder 25: 83)
    3 pages; Social disorganization, Slave girl, Population: Immigration; Chinese; Northern California
  - "Interview with Dr. E. E. Chandler," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 23 (Box-folder 25: 84)
    5 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture, Racial traits, Race consciousness, Investigations; Hindu, Japanese, and Mexican; Southern California
  - "My Life History," by Francisco Carino, Los Angeles, California, 1924 August (Box-folder 25: 85)
    11 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness, Heritages, Racial traits; Filipino; Southern California
  - "Life History as a Social Document: Takeuchi," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 14 (Box-folder 25: 86)
    9 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness, Racial traits, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Quotations from a Letter from a Japanese Girl," by Gretchen Tuthill (Box-folder 25: 87)
    2 pages; Americanization: Family problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - Press notices from Long Beach Press regarding permission granted for church: Long Beach property owners warned, 1923 May 9 (Box-folder 25: 88)
    12 pages; Race consciousness, Communities, Goodwill: Religious activities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "An Investigation of Two Specific Instances of Racial Conflict in Long Beach, California, in Connection with the Survey of Race Relations," by Frances Lucas and Gretchen Tuthill, University of Southern California, 1924 June (Box-folder 25: 89)
    18 pages; Race consciousness, Communities, Goodwill: Religious activities; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interview with Yasuhei Takeawa, 1924 July 7 (Box-folder 25: 90)
    7 pages; Life histories, Goodwill, Racial traits, Americanization: Accommodation; Japanese; Seattle
  - Digital copy of Box 26
  - Copy of letter from T. Sowa to Ruth H. Greiner, 1924 July 26 (Box-folder 26: 91)
    4 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Accommodation, Racial traits, Racial consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "A Comparative Study of the Japanese Question in California," interview with Japanese laborer, S. Antomy, Santa Paula, California, by Loreita Balcom, 1923 December 29 (Box-folder 26: 92)
    4 pages; Life histories, Competition and land: Labor, Heritages; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with L. C. Lee, El Centro, California," by William C. Smith, 1924 June (Box-folder 26: 93)
    4 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture and Labor; Japanese, Hindu, Filipino, and Mexican; Southern California
  - "Interview with Adjutant Masasuke Kobayashi," Head of Japanese Branch of Salvation Army, by William C. Smith, 1924 September 12 (Box-folder 26: 94)
    4 pages; Goodwill: Religious activities, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Opinion on Orientals (anti), letter from Eva Martin, Los Angeles (Box-folder 26: 95)
    2 pages; Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interview with H. H. Clark, manager of Colorado River Land Company, Mexicali, Mexico (Box-folder 26: 96)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture and labor; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Shigeichi Okami," East San Pedro, California, by William C. Smith, 1924 August 25 (Box-folder 26: 97)
    1 page; Life histories, Americanization: Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Frank Ishi," by William C. Smith, 1924 September 19 (Box-folder 26: 98)
    7 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Family problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Y. Nakasugi," East San Pedro, by William C. Smith, 1924 August 25 (Box-folder 26: 99)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Vocational problems, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Kazuo Kawai," Los Angeles, by William C. Smith, 1924 August 7 (Box-folder 26: 100)
    7 pages; Americanization: Vocational problems and education, Goodwill: Religious activities, Heritages; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Conversation with a Los Angeles Japanese Minister" (name preferred withheld), by Chloe Holt, Los Angeles, 1924 July (Box-folder 26: 101)
    4 pages; Americanization: Vocational problems and education, Race consciousness, Goodwill: Religious activities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mrs. Machida," Los Angeles, California, by Chloe Holt, 1924 July 2 (Box-folder 26: 102)
    5 pages; Intermarriage, Americanization, Racial traits; Chinese and Japanese; Southern California
  - "How the Japanese Won a Foothold," Farm and Tractor Magazine, Los Angeles Times, 1924 August 17 (Box-folder 26: 103)
    3 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Southern California
  - Visit with a white woman married to a Japanese (name withheld by request), Los Angeles, California, by Chloe Holt, 1924 August 14 (Box-folder 26: 104)
    7 pages; Intermarriage; Japanese; Southern California
  - Suggested topics for Japanese Students Christian Association, and letter to William C. Smith from Kazuo Kawai, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 26: 105)
    3 pages; Americanization, Goodwill: Religious activities; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interview with Lee H.---, 1924 September 29 (Box-folder 26: 106)
    5 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - An American-born Japanese in America, J. Sato (Box-folder 26: 107)
    5 pages; Race consciousness, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - A wedding in Chinese and in American (Box-folder 26: 108)
    4 pages; Heritages, Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - "The Confession of a Japanese Servant," extracts from Independent, New York, 1905 September 21 (Box-folder 26: 109)
    18 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness, Racial traits, Other: Industry; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interview with N. Hiroshi, Los Angeles (Box-folder 26: 110)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Vocational problems and second generation, Population: Movement; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Names of People Seen in Connection with Pico Heights, Los Angeles, Conflict," by Chloe Holt, 1924 July (Box-folder 26: 111)
    44 pages; Competition and land, Race consciousness, Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - Report, Oriental and agriculture, Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, California (Box-folder 26: 112)
    4 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Southern California
  - "I Am Only a Foreigner – So This Is America," letter by a Filipino boy to an Americanization teacher, Los Angeles, by William C. Smith (Box-folder 26: 113)
    6 pages; Race consciousness; Filipino; Southern California
  - Report, Long Beach Chamber of Commerce, regarding Japanese situation, 1924 March 5 (Box-folder 26: 114)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture, Investigations; Japanese; Southern California
  - Resolutions passed at Annual Convention of Japanese Association of Southern California (Box-folder 26: 115)
    1 page; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Mrs. Manspeaker's Americanization class, 1924 May 20 (Box-folder 26: 116)
    5 pages; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Personal Experiences with the Japanese Children," by Marjorie McComber, 1924 May 22 (Box-folder 26: 117)
    6 pages; Americanization, Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "A Japanese Agricultural Community near Fullerton, California," paper by Marjorie McComber, 1924 May 26 (Box-folder 26: 118)
    6 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Southern California
  - "American Board Mission," letter to missionary ladies of Penchou Shansi, China, by Gordon Riegler (Box-folder 26: 119)
    6 pages; Life histories; Chinese; Southern California
  - Interview with Americanization teacher, Los Angeles County (Box-folder 26: 120)
    7 pages; Race consciousness, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Dr. Keitoku Watanabe," a Japanese dentist, Los Angeles, California, by Chloe Holt, 1924 August 22 (Box-folder 26: 121)
    5 pages; Americanization, Competition and land: Agriculture, Intermarriage; Japanese; Southern California
  - "A Short Sketch of My Life," by Theodore Fieldbrave (Box-folder 26: 122)
    5 pages; Life histories, Goodwill: Religious activities; Heritages, Hindu; Northern California
  - Letter from the chairman, National Oriental Committee of the American Legion [Thomas N. Swale?], to Robert L. Owen regarding Takao Ozawa's suit for naturalization, 1923 August 14 (Box-folder 26: 123)
    5 pages; Race consciousness, Investigations; Japanese; Northern California
  - Letter from Sei Fujii, President of Japanese Association of Los Angeles, to J. Kasai, Secretary of Japanese Association regarding anti-sentiment letter to sheriff from Japanese consul, 1923 March 6 (Box-folder 26: 124)
    4 pages; Race consciousness: Prejudice and conflict; Japanese; Southern California
  - Notes by McClatchy secured from L. B. Landsborough, Sacramento County, manager of A. B. Humphrey's orchard and vineyard, 1924 January 4 (Box-folder 26: 125)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture and labor; Northern California
  - Warning against survey of race relations issued by Chamber of Commerce, Portland, 1923 November 17 (Box-folder 26: 126)
    2 pages; Race consciousness: Public opinion, Other: Organization; Oregon
  - "Interview with Mrs. Teresasa," matron and interpreter for Oriental women, Angel Island, California, by Mrs. R. E. Park (Box-folder 26: 127)
    5 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Northern California
  - Letter to R. Mason from Dorothy Gee, a young Chinese girl, after her return to China, 1923 June 23 (Box-folder 26: 128)
    4 pages; Race consciousness, Racial traits; Chinese; Northern California
  - An interview with Donaldina Cameron, letter to Miss Cameron from Office of the Commissioner, Angel Island (Box-folder 26: 129)
    6 pages; Social disorganization: Vice and crime, Goodwill: Religious activities; Chinese; Northern California
  - Reminiscences of Mrs. Fremont's older Japanese servants (Box-folder 26: 130)
    2 pages; Racial traits, Competition and land: Labor; Japanese; Northern California
  - Letter from a Burmese theological student to a missionary from The Christian Century, 1924 September 18 (Box-folder 26: 131)
    2 pages; Race consciousness, Goodwill: Religious activities; Hindu; Northern California
  - Interview on Asiatic labor with Neumann, manager of Lyndon Hotel, Los Gatos, California, 1924 April 5 (Box-folder 26: 132)
    3 pages; Race consciousness; Filipino and Japanese; Northern California
  - Interview with Tom Lee, cook for Dr. N. C. Peterson, Stockton, California (Box-folder 26: 133)
    2 pages; Life histories; Chinese; Northern California
  - Visit, George Shima, "Potato King" of California, by Mrs. Park, 1924 July 14 (Box-folder 26: 134)
    3 pages; Americanization; Japanese; Northern California
  - "Impressions," by Mineko K. Inui (Box-folder 26: 135)
    9 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Northern California
  - Statement on Orientals and agriculture by Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce (Box-folder 26: 136)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Experiences of man, Fresno, California, regarding Japanese (Box-folder 26: 137)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interviews with Hughes, night watchman, regarding Stevens Lake situation, 1924 June 11 (Box-folder 26: 138)
    3 pages; Competition and land, Other: Industry; Japanese; Oregon
  - Interview with native son of Oregon regarding Stevens Lake situation (Box-folder 26: 139)
    1 page; Competition and land, Race consciousness; Japanese; Oregon
  - Interviews with field officer regarding Stevens Lake situation (Box-folder 26: 140)
    1 page; Competition and land, Other: Industry; Japanese; Oregon
  - Interviews with an electrician regarding Stevens Lake situation (Box-folder 26: 141)
    1 page; Competition and land, Other: Industry, Race consciousness; Japanese; Oregon
  - Interview with logger regarding Stevens Lake situation (Box-folder 26: 142)
  - Interviews with J. B. Fitzgerald, regarding Stevens Lake strike, letter to Robert E. Park, 1924 May 3 (Box-folder 26: 143)
    3 pages; Competition and land, Other: Industry, Race consciousness; Japanese; Oregon
  - The Okajima girls (Box-folder 26: 144)
    1 page; Intermarriage, Americanization; Japanese; Northern California
  - Life history of Kanaye Magasawa, Santa Rosa, California (Box-folder 26: 145)
    3 pages; Life histories, Competition and land: Agriculture, Goodwill, Americanization: Accommodation; Japanese; Northern California
  - Digital copy of Box 27
  - Story of Wong Ah So, 1924 August 1 (Box-folder 27: 146)
    3 pages; Life histories, Social disorganization, Slave girls, Heritages; Chinese; Northern California
  - "Slave Girls," press reports (Box-folder 27: 147)
    5 pages; Social disorganization, Slave girls; Chinese; Northern California
  - Life of Ah Seen, tubercular case (Box-folder 27: 148)
    1 page; Social disorganization: Disease, Other: Industry; Chinese; Northern California
  - Miscellaneous accounts, factory conditions (Box-folder 27: 149)
    2 pages; Competition and land, Other: Industry; Chinese; Northern California
  - The history and problem of Angel Island, California, 1924 March (Box-folder 27: 150)
    15 pages; Population: Immigration, Investigations: Historical; Northern California
  - Biography of a boy, Seattle High School (Box-folder 27: 151)
    3 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Japanese; Seattle
  - "The Life Story of Mohan Singh," by Miss Secord (Box-folder 27: 152)
    8 pages; Life histories; Hindu; Seattle
  - Letter to Miss Greiner from Atsushi Miyanaga, Japanese student, 1924 May 2 (Box-folder 27: 153)
    2 pages; Race consciousness, Life histories; Japanese; Seattle
  - Interview with Mrs. Peter Mayberg (Box-folder 27: 154)
    4 pages; Communities, Social disorganization: Vice and crime, Tongs; Seattle
  - Interview with Hatsumi Sakaguchi (Box-folder 27: 155)
    3 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Seattle
  - Interview with T. Torikai, 1924 July 8 (Box-folder 27: 156)
    6 pages; Life histories, Intermarriage; Japanese; Seattle
  - Interview with Masao Murakami, Reverend Morton, interpreter (Box-folder 27: 157)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Seattle
  - Interview with Mrs. Masa Higashida, 1924 June 24 (Box-folder 27: 158)
    4 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Seattle